checkvist.com 2019-10-02

# Privacy policy | Checkvist

This is the privacy policy for the Checkvist web service. Here we describe what personal information we collect, how we use it, and your options regarding information we may collect about you. If you have questions, please feel free to contact us at [kirsa@checkvist.com](mailto:kirsa@checkvist.com)

**We value your privacy, and strive to make our services safe and enjoyable to everyone. Checkvist stores only the essential personal information, required for the tool functioning. We will never, under no circumstances, sell this data to anyone.**

We aggregate information about people navigating through the website pages: landing pages, time spent, page scrolling, etc. This information is anonymous, besides the country and IP address. More in the Google Analytics and HotJar sections below. 

### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics as the main tool to understand our service visitors' demographics and the conversion process. For more detailed information on the Google Analytics privacy policy, please read Google's [Terms](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/) and [Privacy policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). 

_**Google Analytics is not used on your account data. We track only the website landing pages navigation and the fact of a successful registration. Once you've logged in or created a Checkvist account, Google Analytics tracking is disabled completely.**_

### HotJar

We use HotJar to better understand how people interact with our services, in particular, we follow the initial experience and the onboarding process (web site pages visited or scrolled, screen resolutions and device used, user interface controls clicked, etc). For more detailed information on HotJar's privacy and security policies, please visit <https://www.hotjar.com/privacy>. 

_**HotJar is not used on your account data. Once you've logged in or created a Checkvist account, HotJar tracking is disabled completely.**_

We do not use any tracking or monitoring tools in your account.

When you create a Checkvist account, we ask for your email address, username, and password. This data is used solely for the authentication and necessary email communication.

### Emails

  * **Email verification** Shortly after the registration you'll receive an email from us, asking to verify the email address you used for Checkvist registration. Unless you do it, Checkvist collaboration features will be disabled. 
  * **PRO account trial started** If you start a PRO account trial, we send you a confirmation email with the list of all the new features you can use as a PRO client. 
  * **PRO trial is about to end** We do not limit PRO account trial time, and before your PRO account trial has ended, we send you an email offering to prolong the trial. 
  * **Account upgrade to PRO** After you've paid for a PRO account, we send you a confirmation email with the payment terms and available feature list. 
  * **Next payment notification** If you have an active Checkvist PRO subscription, we send a reminder about the next coming payment 7 days before it's due. If you have Checkvist PRO plan without a subscription, we send a reminder 14 days before it is going to end. Thus you can review your account and decide on the next payment. 
  * **Collaboration and notification emails** Checkvist sends email notifications 
    1. When you share a list via email,
    2. When you are an assignee for a task,
    3. For due tasks or list edits.
You can share lists via hyperlinks to avoid the first, and configure or disable all automated due and change notifications for your account, at any time. 
  * **Group account emails** Checkvist sends an email notification to people who are added to a group PRO account and when they are removed from it. 
  * **Security issues and service availability emails** We are obliged by law to inform affected customers about the security issues and steps taken to fix them. Besides, we retain the right to inform customers about service availability issues. 

**We do not send any marketing, customer research or advertising emails. All news and updates are distributed via in-app notifications,[Checkvist blog](https://blog.checkvist.com/), and social media accounts**: [Twitter](https://twitter.com/checkvist_news), [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/checkvist). 

###  Dropbox via Checkvist—Dropbox integration

One of the PRO plan features is keeping backup files in your Dropbox account. If you set up this integration, your files will be stored in your Dropbox, under Dropbox own [Privacy policy](https://www.dropbox.com/privacy) and [Terms](https://www.dropbox.com/terms). 

### Applications using Checkvist Open API

Checkvist API allows to create a custom integration with other applications and share you data with them. In this case all shared data will be governed by privacy policy and terms of those applications. 

For _non-authenticated user_ Checkvist does not use cookies directly, but only for third-party services:

  * Google Analytics ([Terms](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/) and [Privacy policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)) 
  * HotJar ([Terms](https://www.hotjar.com/terms) and [Privacy policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy)) 

For _authenticated user_ , Checkvist uses cookies to store some visitors preferences and session information, related to service functioning. Cookies are required to use Checkvist.

If you have checked the "Remember me" option upon log in, the cookie will be stored during a 90 day period. After that it will expire to protect you against others accidentally accessing your account contents, and you will have to log in again.

If you haven't checked the "Remember me" option, cookies will be cleared when you close your browser and next time you will have to log in again.

For a more detailed description see the Cookies page.

To stop automatic bot sign ups and unsolicited email distribution, we employ Google Invisible reCAPTCHA. By creating a Checkvist account you agree to Google reCAPTCHA [Terms](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/) and [Privacy policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

We require an explicit email verification for features that employ email distribution from the system (list sharing and notifications).

We use third party vendors and hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and related technology required to run Checkvist. Although we own the code, databases, and all rights to the Checkvist application, you retain all rights to your data. 

### Database data (users, lists data, history)

All database data, including users, lists, and history, are stored on the dedicated server(s) at [LeaseWeb](https://www.leaseweb.com/) (Netherlands). 

For inactive non-PRO users, the data is removed after 1 year of inactivity (with prior two email warnings about data deletion in a case of inactivity). 

For all active users, and for all paying customers, the data is stored as long as the person keeps the account in Checkvist. 

### File attachments and individual data backups

File attachments and individual data backups are stored in Amazon AWS/Ireland.

### Full service backups

Full Checkvist backups, together with database and servers, are stored in Amazon AWS/Ireland. 

### Payment information

Personal information from payments is stored only at our payment processors, [FastSpring](https://fastspring.com/) (and [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/cz/home), for older non-EU customers). **No information about credit cards (or other means of payment) is ever transferred to Checkvist servers.**

Such information as payment email address, country, and address, is stored in internal Checkvist server logs and removed within 1 month after the payment. Also it is present in the email confirmations about payments for audit purposes. 

### Service logs

Checkvist service logs contain details about user activity and service operations. They are stored on the dedicated server(s) at [LeaseWeb](https://www.leaseweb.com/) (Netherlands), and contain information about 1 month of activity. 

Passwords are filtered out from the logs. 

We do not partner or have any relationship with any online advertising companies.

We reserve the right to disclose personally identifiable information under special circumstances, such as to comply with subpoenas or when your actions violate the  Terms of Service.

If you want to erase all data, associated with your Checkvist account (including payment history, email address, all list data, attachments, etc.), just log in and delete your account on the [profile page](https://checkvist.com/auth/profile#status). That operation can not be undone, and will permanently delete _all your data_ , including those shared with other people. 

To export your lists before deletion, use the ['Export' command](https://checkvist.com/auth/help#import_and_export) in the list's toolbar or use OPML backup files [(PRO feature)](https://checkvist.com/auth/help#pro). If you don't have a PRO account, you can request a copy of all your lists and personal data, associated with your account. Please, contact [privacy@checkvist.com](mailto:privacy@checkvist.com). We'll send you the file within 30 working days. 

We may periodically update this policy. In this case we will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the email address specified in your Checkvist account or by placing a prominent notice on our site. 

_Last updated: May, 20 2018_
